<topics>
<top>
<num> 601
</num><title> Turkey Iraq water

</title><desc> Description:
What is the effect of Turkish river control projects on Iraqi
water resources?


</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document will deal specifically with water issues
between Turkey and Iraq.  Other political and economic
concerns between the two countries (e.g. the Kurds or
water to Syria, Israel and Lebanon) are not relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 602
</num><title> Czech, Slovak sovereignty

</title><desc> Description:
Retrieve information regarding the process by which the
Czech and Slovak republics of Czechoslovakia established
separate sovereign countries.


</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document will provide specific dates and details
regarding the separation movement.  Documents relating to
normal activities of the separate nations, both internal and
external are not relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 603
</num><title> Tobacco cigarette lawsuit

</title><desc> Description:
Retrieve documents regarding U.S. lawsuits against the tobacco industry
for causing health problems and/or death from cigarettes.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents must contain who, where and why details, and must be
about a specific suit or suits.  Specific documents are relevant
regardless of the outcome of the suit.  Documents concerning lawsuits
about fraud, lack of warning, and nicotine 'spiking' are all relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 604
</num><title> Lyme disease arthritis

</title><desc> Description:
What evidence is there to link tick-borne Lyme disease with arthritis?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents providing evidence to support or refute the connection
between Lyme disease and arthritis are relevant.  Documents discussing
Lyme disease and inflammatory joint disorder are also relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 605
</num><title> Great Britain health care

</title><desc> Description:
What are the pros and cons of Great Britain's universal health
care system?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents that discuss recommendations for change or list criticisms
of the current system are relevant.  Documents about an individual's
experience with the health care system in Great Britain are irrelevant
unless the document also contains a specific recommendation or criticism.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 606
</num><title> leg traps ban 

</title><desc> Description:
Find documents that discuss banning leg traps used to capture animals.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Both 'leg traps' and 'steel-jawed traps' are relevant.
Documents describing related prohibitions, such as banning the
sale of furs when the animals are caught using leg traps, are
also relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 607
</num><title> human genetic code

</title><desc> Description:
What progress is being made in the effort to map and sequence
the human genetic code?


</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents must discuss specific progress in mapping the
human genome.  Documents that simply describe applications of
the research, such as using DNA in criminal cases,
using the genetic code to treat disease, or creating
genetically engineered organisms are irrelevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 608
</num><title> taxing social security 

</title><desc> Description:
Find articles that discuss the pros and cons of taxing U.S. social
security benefits.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Only documents that discuss income tax on social security benefits in
the U.S. are relevant.  Documents that discuss the social security tax
itself or other countries' taxation are irrelevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 609
</num><title> per capita alcohol consumption

</title><desc> Description:
Find documents that discuss per capita consumption of alcohol by 
political entity---country, state, province, etc.


</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents that provide per capita figures for specific beverages
such as beer, wine, or spirits are relevant.  However, to be relevant
documents must provide specific figures on alcohol consumption:
documents that simply discuss trends without providing specific
figures are not relevant.  Documents with figures for world
per capita consumption are also relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 610
</num><title> minimum wage adverse impact

</title><desc> Description:
Find claims made by U.S. small businesses regarding the adverse
impact on their businesses of raising the minimum wage.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document will include a specific reason for opposition
to raising the minimum wage by U.S. small businesses.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 611
</num><title> Kurds Germany violence

</title><desc> Description:
What violent activities have Kurds, or members of the
Workers Party of Kurdistan (PKK), carried out in Germany?


</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents contain information on the types of violent,
destructive, or terroristic activities perpetrated by Kurds
or members of the Workers Party of Kurdistan (PKK) in Germany.
Information on whom or what is targeted by these kinds of acts is
also relevant.  Relevant activities include: killing or wounding
of individuals; destruction or burning of property; and rioting.
Relevant activities must be both attributed to Kurds or the PKK
and occur in Germany.  Violence by Kurds or the PKK against other
Kurds or PKK members is relevant if it occurs in Germany, though self
immolation is irrelevant.  Peaceful demonstrations in Germany
are irrelevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 612
</num><title> Tibet protesters

</title><desc> Description:
What has been the outcome for the pro-independence protesters in Tibet
who were arrested by Chinese authorities?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents containing information on the sentencing, releasing and/or
treatment of arrested protesters are relevant.  Only arrests for
anti-Chinese/pro-independence (for Tibet) are relevant; criminal
arrests are irrelevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 613
</num><title> Berlin wall disposal

</title><desc> Description:
How were pieces of the Berlin wall disposed of after their removal?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents contain specific instances of the fate of pieces of
the Berlin wall.  Example uses such as selling or taking pieces
as souvenirs or using pieces in monuments are relevant.  However,
the simple fact of the wall's removal is not relevant, nor are schemes
and plans that were not implemented.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 614
</num><title> Flavr Savr tomato

</title><desc> Description:
Find information about the first genetically modified food product to
go on the market, Flavr Savr (also Flavor Saver) Tomato developed by
Calgene.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents about genetically engineered food in general are not relevant;
relevant documents must include specifics regarding the Flavr Savr
tomato.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 615
</num><title> timber exports Asia

</title><desc> Description:
What is the extent of U.S. raw timber exports to Asia, and what effect
do these exports have on the U.S. lumber industry?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents containing information about economic or environmental
concerns related to the export of timber to Asia are relevant.
Documents must specifically address exports to Asia, rather than
the timber industry in general, to be relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 616
</num><title> Volkswagen Mexico 

</title><desc> Description:
What is the history and extent of Volkswagen production in Mexico?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents must contain information specific to 
Volkswagen production in Mexico.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 617
</num><title> Russia Cuba economy

</title><desc> Description:
What effect has the reduction of Russian support had on the Cuban economy?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents must contain information specific to how the
reduction of Russian support has affected the Cuban economy.
Documents referring to the state of the Cuban economy but not mentioning
Russia are irrelevant, as are documents describing joint Russo-Cuban
projects.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 618
</num><title> Ayatollah Khomeini death

</title><desc> Description:
Find documents that describe the death of Iranian President
Ayatollah Khomeini and the ramifications of his death.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents must contain substantive information regarding
the death of Khomeini; incidental mentions of his death are not relevant.
Documents about the movement Khomeini led when alive are not relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 619
</num><title> Winnie Mandela scandal 

</title><desc> Description:
What part did Winnie Mandela herself play in the kidnapping, beating
and murder scandal in South Africa in December 1988 through January 1989?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents must contain some mention of what Mandela's personal involvement
may have been to be relevant.  Documents about her conviction on
charges stemming from the scandal are relevant, though her protestations
of innocence are irrelevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 620
</num><title> France nuclear testing

</title><desc> Description:
How has France responded to protests against its nuclear testing in the
South Pacific?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
A document containing information regarding any type of protest
by any one is relevant as long as France's response is also included
in the document.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 621
</num><title> women ordained Church of England

</title><desc> Description:
What are the arguments for and against Great Britain's approval
of women being ordained as Church of England priests?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents primarily about voting on the matter by church officials
and the British parliament are relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 622
</num><title> price fixing 

</title><desc> Description:
Identify companies or corporations that have been accused or indicted of
price fixing including the product or type of product involved.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents must contain both the company and the product involved.
Documents about price fixing by the stock market are not relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 623
</num><title> toxic chemical weapon

</title><desc> Description:
Gather any information that mentions ricin, sarin, soman, or anthrax as a
toxic chemical used as a weapon.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
To be relevant, a document must pertain to the use of toxic chemicals
as weapons.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 624
</num><title> SDI Star Wars

</title><desc> Description:
What are the pros and cons of developing the Strategic Defense
Initiative (SDI) also known as "Star Wars"?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document must contain information regarding the technical
aspects of the Strategic Defense Initiative (SDI).  Documents containing
simple statements that SDI is part of the U.S. defense strategy,
or that discuss funding or arms reduction treaties related
to SDI but do not discuss the technical aspects are irrelevant.  Documents
containing statements by the administration that SDI capabilities
had been oversold are relevant. 
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 625
</num><title> arrests bombing WTC

</title><desc> Description:
Identify documents that provide information on the arrest and/or
conviction of the bombers of the World Trade Center (WTC) in February 1993.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document must contain information about an arrest
or conviction related to the bombing.  Simple claims of involvement
are not relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 626
</num><title> human stampede 

</title><desc> Description:
Find reports of human stampedes that have resulted in 20 or more deaths.


</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents that mention people being killed by animal stampedes are not
relevant.  Relevant documents could mention human stampedes in any public
place such as a sporting event, bar, restaurant or entertainment event.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 627
</num><title> Russian food crisis

</title><desc> Description:
What steps are being taken by the U.S. to help Russia solve the food crisis
in Russia?


</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document must contain information specific to U.S.
involvement (actual or planned) to alleviate the Russian food crisis.
Documents describing Russia's internal food shortage debates,
statistics depicting the severity of the shortage, or other
countries' involvement are not relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 628
</num><title> U.S. invasion of Panama

</title><desc> Description:
What justification was used by the U.S. government to invade Panama,
and why did some oppose the invasion?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents must include specific reference to the
U.S. government's justification for the invasion.
Documents simply noting support for or criticism of the
invasion by other governments are not relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 629
</num><title> abortion clinic attack 

</title><desc> Description:
What is the incidence of violent attacks on abortion clinics and the
doctors and staff of the clinics by anti-abortionists?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents describing bombings and arson attacks on an abortion clinic,
or other violent, destructive actions, are relevant.  Violent attacks
on doctors and staff, including shootings, are also relevant.
Reports of attempted attacks are relevant.   Reports of non-violent
activities such as trespassing, picketing, etc. are irrelevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 630
</num><title> Gulf War Syndrome 

</title><desc> Description:
Retrieve documents containing information about the symptoms
of individuals suffering from 'Gulf War Syndrome' as a result
of serving in the Gulf War.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents regarding law suits that claim causes of illness from service
in the Gulf War are relevant, as are reports of cases resulting from
contact with an ill Gulf War veteran.  'Dessert Storm Syndrome' is
a synonym for the condition and is considered relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 631
</num><title> Mandela South Africa President

</title><desc> Description:
Find documents relating to the election of Nelson Mandela as president
of the Republic of South Africa.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents must include specific information about Mandela becoming
president of South Africa to be relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 632
</num><title> southeast Asia tin mining

</title><desc> Description:
What are the major tin mining countries in southeast Asia?


</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant document contain information about tin mining in southeast
Asia. Countries considered to be in southeast Asia include
China, Malaysia, Indonesia, Viet Nam, Burma, Thailand and Laos.  
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 633
</num><title> Welsh devolution 

</title><desc> Description:
What is the history of the Welsh devolution movement?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents contain information about some aspect of the
Welsh devolution movement.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 634
</num><title> L-tryptophan deaths

</title><desc> Description:
How many deaths are attributed to having taken tainted L-tryptophan
dietary supplements?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document will describe a specific case of death attributed to
tainted L=tryptophan or will give figures regarding total
number of deaths.  Reports of illness caused by the supplement
that did not result in death are not relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 635
</num><title> doctor assisted suicides

</title><desc> Description:
What are the arguments for and against doctor assisted suicide in the U.S.?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document must contain a viewpoint regarding doctor
assisted suicide to be relevant.  Reports describing actual
doctor assisted suicides are not relevant unless the document
also presents a pro or con argument.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 636
</num><title> jury duty exemptions

</title><desc> Description:
Find documents that discuss reasons why people may be exempted from
serving on a jury.


</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document must include a specific reason that provides
an exemption or list an occupation that causes exemption from jury duty.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 637
</num><title> human growth hormone (HGH)

</title><desc> Description:
What are the pros and cons of adults using human growth hormone (HGH)?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document must discuss a specific application of human growth
hormone in adults.  Documents about using growth hormone to help
short children are irrelevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 638
</num><title> wrongful convictions

</title><desc> Description:
Find documents that discuss freed prisoners who have been wrongfully
convicted based on faulty forensic evidence, poor police work, or false
testimony.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents about political prisoners who were freed because of
incompetent prosecutions are relevant.   However, documents that
discuss prisoners who are pardoned or released on bond when their
convictions are overturned are not relevant, nor are
documents about prisoners freed to make a political
statement or prisoners freed for an exchange.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 639
</num><title> consumer on-line shopping

</title><desc> Description:
What factors contributed to the growth of consumer on-line
shopping?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document will describe a factor that has contributed
to the increase use of on-line shopping by consumers.  Documents
containing statistical data supporting a growth factor are
also relevant. 
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 640
</num><title> maternity leave policies

</title><desc> Description:
What are the maternity leave policies of various governments?


</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents will contain specific details about a
legally-mandated maternity leave policy.  Current or passed
legislation is relevant, but proposed or in-process legislation is not.
Vetoes of bills for maternity leave are irrelevant.  Legislation that
is passed, but not yet enacted (i.e. to take effect at a specific
time in future) is relevant.  Issues of cost to businesses and/or
government are irrelevant.  Statements to the effect of what benefits
are not provided are relevant.  
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 641
</num><title> Valdez wildlife marine life

</title><desc> Description:
What was the impact of the Exxon Valdez oil spill on the marine life
and wildlife of the area?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents must have some specific detail, such as types of
animals, the kinds of problems found, and outcome (such as number
of animals saved or dead).
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 642
</num><title> Tiananmen Square protesters

</title><desc> Description:
What happened to protesters arrested in connection with the Tiananmen
Square demonstrations in Beijing in the spring of 1989?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents must be attributed to the Tiananmen Square demonstrations to
be relevant: documents about protests elsewhere in response to Tiananmen
Square are not relevant.  Specific names, etc. are not necessary for a
document to be relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 643
</num><title> salmon dams Pacific northwest

</title><desc> Description:
What harm have power dams in the Pacific northwest
caused to salmon fisheries?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
To be relevant, a document must include at least one negative impact of
dams on the salmon population in the U.S. Pacific northwest.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 644
</num><title> exotic animals import

</title><desc> Description:
Identify documents that discuss exotic species of animals that are
imported into the U.S. or U.K.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents about importing birds are relevant.  Documents about
importing insects or pests are not relevant.  Discussion of exotic
animal diseases is not relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 645
</num><title> software piracy

</title><desc> Description:
Find documents that discuss the financial impact of software piracy upon
the software-producing industry.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents must specifically include software piracy:
documents that lump the piracy of video, music, software, etc.
together are not relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 646
</num><title> food stamps increase

</title><desc> Description:
Find documents that discuss an increase in the number of people receiving
food stamp benefits.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents that discuss changes in the law allowing more eligible food
stamp recipients are relevant.  Documents that imply that a certain group
of people, such as immigrants, will be eligible for food stamps are also
relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 647
</num><title> windmill electricity

</title><desc> Description:
Has the use of windmill technology to generate electricity been
economically productive?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document will contain a comparison of the costs of
generating electricity through the use of windmills to other
more conventional means of generation.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 648
</num><title> family leave law

</title><desc> Description:
Identify documents that discuss details of a family leave law, such as
how long, compensation, if any, for what reason allowed, etc.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document must contain some detail about a family leave law
to be relevant.  The mere mention of the existence of such a law
is not relevant.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 649
</num><title> computer viruses

</title><desc> Description:
How do computers get infected by computer viruses? 

</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document will discuss a means by which a computer can
become a host to a computer virus.
</narr></top>



<top>
<num> 650
</num><title> tax evasion indicted

</title><desc> Description:
Identify individuals or corporations that have been indicted
on charges of tax evasion of more than two million dollars in
the U.S. or U.K.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
A relevant document will contain details about large-scale tax
evasion.  Documents about people who lost in excess of two million
dollars as a result of doing business with an organization indicted
for tax fraud are relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 651

</num><title>
U.S. ethnic population

</title><desc> Description:
How is the ethnic make-up of the U.S. population changing?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents must indicate a shift in the ethnic make-up of the U.S.
population.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 652

</num><title>
OIC Balkans 1990s

</title><desc>
What was the OIC's involvement in the Balkans in 1990-94?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents describe the role the OIC played in the
Balkan region.  Also relevant are documents reflecting
the Balkans' players (nations, groups) positions pro or
con regarding OIC involvement.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 653

</num><title>
ETA Basque terrorism

</title><desc>
Find documents that describe the activities of ETA,
the Basque terrorist organization, in Spain.

</desc><narr>
Non-ETA politicians' comments/speculation regarding the organization
are not relevant, nor are descriptions of ETA activities outside of Spain.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 654

</num><title>
same-sex schools

</title><desc>
What are the advantages and disadvantages of same-sex schools?

</desc><narr>
Any discussion of the relative merits of same-sex schooling is relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 655

</num><title>
ADD diagnosis treatment

</title><desc>
How is Attention Deficit Disorder (ADD) diagnosed and treated in
young children?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents specifically address diagnosis and/or treatment
of ADD.  Simple definitions and descriptions of ADD are not relevant.
Documents that discuss studies that could lead to treatment are relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 656

</num><title>
lead poisoning children

</title><desc>
How are young children being protected against lead poisoning from paint
and water pipes?

</desc><narr>
Documents describing the extent of the problem, including
suits against manufacturers and product recalls, are relevant.
Descriptions of future plans for lead poisoning abatement projects
are also relevant.  Worker problems with lead are not relevant.  Other
poison hazards for children are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 657

</num><title>
school prayer banned

</title><desc>
Has prayer in U.S. schools been banned completely?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents discuss circumstances under which some schools
continue to permit prayer and court rulings on the same.  Prayer in
non-public schools is relevant, but prayer in schools outside the
U.S. is not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 658

</num><title>
teenage pregnancy

</title><desc>
Find documents that discuss teenage pregnancy in the United States:
the birth rate for teenage mothers, causes and results of
teenage pregnancies, and steps taken to reduce the number of
teenage pregnancies.

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents will discuss teenage pregnancy in the United States.
Also relevant is information on teenage abortions.
</narr></top>


<top>

<num> 659

</num><title>
cruise health safety

</title><desc>
What standards do cruise ships use for health and safety maintenance?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents refer to health and safety practices and standards for
recreational cruise ships.  Not relevant are standards for small pleasure craft
or commercial freight ships, tankers, etc.  Documents referring to a specific
ship's problems are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>

<num> 660

</num><title>
whale watching California

</title><desc>
Find information about whale watching off the coast of California.

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents make mention of one or more Californian site or
guide services for watching whales in their habitat.
</narr></top>


<top>

<num> 661

</num><title>
melanoma treatment causes

</title><desc>
What are the causes and treatments for melanoma?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents describe causes, diagnosis, and/or treatment of
melanoma.  Articles on research being conducted that could lead to
diagnosis or treatment are also relevant.  Articles on other diseases,
including other skin cancers, are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>

<num> 662

</num><title>
telemarketer protection

</title><desc>
How can consumers protect against telemarketers?

</desc><narr>
Relevant are documents describing legislation, regulations, or
strategies that help protect consumers against either telemarketing
scams or unwanted interruptions by telemarketers.  Not relevant are
documents describing telemarketing as a business.  General complaints
about telemarketing are not relevant.  "900" number calls are not
relevant since they are made by the consumer.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 663

</num><title>
Agent Orange exposure

</title><desc>
What were the health effects of Vietnam veterans' exposure
to Agent Orange?

</desc><narr>
Only U.S. veterans' outcomes are relevant.  Information on studies without
results included are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 664

</num><title>
American Indian Museum

</title><desc>
What are the plans for a National Museum of the American Indian?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents will describe the intended location, the types, and
extent of the collections to be housed, and any relationships with
similar museums elsewhere.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 665

</num><title>
poverty Africa sub-Sahara

</title><desc>
How extensive is poverty in sub-Saharan Africa?

</desc><narr>
A relevant document must address the extent of poverty in sub-Saharan Africa.
Items solely about hunger/famine conditions or debt status are not relevant.
Mortality rates around the world compared to sub-Sahara Africa are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 666

</num><title>
Thatcher resignation impact 

</title><desc>
Find documents that discuss the impact Prime Minister Margaret Thatchers'
resignation may have on U.S. and U.K. relations.

</desc><narr>
A relevant document must specifically discuss the impact of Thatcher's
resignation on relations between the U.S. and U.K. 
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 667

</num><title>
unmarried-partner households

</title><desc>
Find documents that discuss the increasing trend toward creation of
unmarried-partner households in the U.S.

</desc><narr>
Reference to any laws pertaining to such households as well as same sex
households are relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 668

</num><title>
poverty, disease

</title><desc>
What is the relationship between poverty and disease?

</desc><narr>
Documents that do not link poverty to diseases directly but mention a
link between poverty and health care are relevant. Documents that simply
mention poverty and disease but do not draw a connection are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 669

</num><title>
Islamic Revolution 

</title><desc>
What were the causes for the Islamic Revolution relative to relations with the
U.S.?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents must discuss the reasons that relations between the Islamic
world and the United States have deteriorated.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 670

</num><title>
U.S. elections apathy 

</title><desc>
Why is there such apathy in U.S. elections?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents must provide reasons for poor turnout at U.S. elections.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 671

</num><title>
Salvation Army benefits

</title><desc>
Find documents that cite the specific benefits the Salvation
Army provides those in need.

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents must cite specific work by the Salvation Army
to help the needy.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 672

</num><title>
NRA membership profile

</title><desc>
Find documents that detail the membership profile of the National
Rifle Association (NRA).

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents provide details such as the age, race, or personality
of NRA members.  Documents that merely state the NRA position on current
issues are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 673

</num><title>
Soviet withdrawal Afghanistan

</title><desc> Description:
What factors led to the withdrawal of Soviet troops from
Afghanistan?

</desc><narr> Narrative:

Documents must provide a reason for the withdrawal; documents
that simply report the fact of the withdrawal are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 674

</num><title>
Greenpeace prosecuted

</title><desc>
Has Greenpeace been prosecuted or its members
arrested for any of its actions?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents concern arrest and/or prosecution of members of
Greenpeace or the organization itself for actions it has taken. 
Suits brought by Greenpeace against others are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 675

</num><title>
Olympics training swimming

</title><desc>
Find information regarding training for Olympic swim meets.

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents will include discussion about
training conditions, sites and requirements. Stories about
individual competitors or about the Olympics in general are
irrelevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 676

</num><title>
poppy cultivation

</title><desc>
Find information on poppy cultivation and export worldwide.

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents contain information specific to the cultivation
of poppy for exportation, including historical reports on the
development of the poppy "industry".  Documents regarding legal
issues or programs to stop cultivation are not relevant.  Incidental
mention of/reference to cultivation, export, smuggling of poppies
or their products in documents with other emphasis are not relevant.
Editorial comment and eradication data are not relevant.  Applications
of U.S. companies to import poppy (for legal purposes) are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 677

</num><title>
Leaning Tower of Pisa

</title><desc>
What efforts are being made to stabilize the Leaning Tower of Pisa,
and how successful have the efforts been?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents provide discussions of the current condition of
the tower, describe reinforcement measures taken, and/or provide
measurements reflecting change in the tower.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 678

</num><title>
joint custody impact

</title><desc>
Find information on joint/shared custody's impact on children.

</desc><narr>
Both economic and emotional impacts on children of divorce are
relevant.  Impact on parents is not relevant unless directly
connected to the children involved.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 679

</num><title>
opening adoption records

</title><desc>
Find documents that discuss the U.S. debate about the
opening of sealed adoption records to adoptees.

</desc><narr>
Only documents referring to court-sanctioned adoptions are
relevant.  Mere descriptions of an individual's
experience are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 680

</num><title>
immigrants Spanish school

</title><desc> Description:
Find documents that discuss how the use of Spanish in
U.S. schools has improved the lives of Mexican immigrants.

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents must discuss how the use of Spanish in school improves the
lives of Spanish-speaking immigrants.  Documents that simply mention
the use of Spanish are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 681

</num><title>
wind power location

</title><desc>
Where are wind power installations located?

</desc><narr>
Documents must provide the location of specific wind power
installations.  Descriptions of wind power installations,
applications to construct installations, and arguments 
for/against wind power are all not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 682

</num><title>
adult immigrants English

</title><desc>
What is being done to teach English to recently
admitted adult immigrants?

</desc><narr>
Descriptions of any program to teach English to adult immigrants
are relevant, as are proposals to establish such programs.
Testing programs and programs targeting only children are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 683

</num><title>
Czechoslovakia breakup

</title><desc>
Find information on the breakup of Czechoslovakia into the
Czech Republic and Slovakia and its social and political impact
on the two countries' people.

</desc><narr>
Editorials are not relevant.  Mention of economic impact and difficulties
are not relevant.  Pre-breakup machinations between the two parties/parts
are relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 684

</num><title>
part-time benefits

</title><desc>
What businesses or government entities give medical
or other benefits to part-time workers?

</desc><narr>
Documents that mention benefits given specifically to part-time
workers are relevant.  Not relevant are benefit plans not
currently in effect, nor benefits given to full-time workers.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 685

</num><title>
Oscar winner selection

</title><desc>
How are Oscar winners selected?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents describe the process by which Oscar
winners are determined, including the methods by which 
potential awardees are selected and nominated, the qualifications
needed to become an eligible voter, and the number of 
eligible voters.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 686

</num><title>
Argentina pegging dollar

</title><desc> Description:
What are the negative impacts of Argentina's policy of pegging
their peso to the U.S. dollar?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Documents must identify problems that have been created due to the
pegging of the peso to the dollar. Documents that mention pegging but
do not identify problems in the Argentine economy are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 687

</num><title>
Northern Ireland industry

</title><desc>
What businesses and industries form the basis of the
economy of Northern Ireland?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents name at least one business or industry
that is a major employer in Northern Ireland.  Documents
about unemployment or industry closing are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 688

</num><title>
non-U.S. media bias

</title><desc>
What bias exists in the media of countries other than the U.S.?

</desc><narr>
Allegations or evidence of bias in the media of countries other
than the U.S. are relevant. External criticism of U.S. media,
i.e., bias allegations against U.S. media by external persons,
is not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 689

</num><title>
family-planning aid

</title><desc>
To which countries does the U.S. provide aid to support family planning,
and for which countries has the U.S. refused or limited support?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents indicate where U.S. aid supports
family planning or where such aid has been denied.
Discussions of why aid for family planning has been refused are
also relevant.  Documents that mention U.S. aid to countries,
but not specifically for family planning are not relevant.
Descriptions of funds for family planning in the U.S. itself are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 690

</num><title>
college education advantage

</title><desc>
Find documents which describe an advantage in hiring potential
or increased income for graduates of U.S. colleges.

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents cite some advantage of a college education
for job opportunities.  Documents citing better opportunities
for non-college vocational-training is not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 691

</num><title>
clear-cutting forests

</title><desc> Description:
What are the objections to the practice of "clear-cutting"?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents discuss the reasons for resistance to the
practice of "clear-cutting."  Discusion of cutting old forests
is not associated with clear-cutting and is not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 692

</num><title>
prostate cancer detection treatment

</title><desc>
Find information on prostate cancer detection and treatment.

</desc><narr>
Different kinds of treatment are relevant, but only when tied to
prostate cancer.  The affliction or treatment of a particular
(well-known) individual is not relevant, nor is treatment or detection
of benign prostate enlargement (BHP).
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 693

</num><title>
newspapers electronic media 

</title><desc>
What has been the effect of the electronic media on the newspaper
industry?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents must explicitly attribute effects to the electronic
media: information about declining readership is irrelevant unless
it attributes the cause to the electronic media.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 694

</num><title>
compost pile 

</title><desc>
How do you make a compost pile?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents must reflect methods or procedures used to create
a compost heap (e.g. dimensions, size, depth, contents or care).
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 695

</num><title>
white collar crime sentence

</title><desc> Description:
What is the usual sentence for those convicted of white
collar crimes?

</desc><narr> Narrative:
To be relevant, a document must indicate the actual sentence
imposed for a white collar crime.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 696

</num><title>
safety plastic surgery

</title><desc>
Find documents that discuss the safety of or the hazards of cosmetic
plastic surgery.

</desc><narr>
Relevant document must refer to a safety issue regarding an elective
cosmetic procedure performed for enhancement of an individual's body
image.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 697

</num><title>
air traffic controller

</title><desc>
What are working conditions and pay for U.S. air traffic controllers?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents tell something about working conditions
or pay for American controllers.  Documents about foreign
controllers or an individual controller are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 698

</num><title>
literacy rates Africa

</title><desc>
What are literacy rates in African countries?

</desc><narr>
A relevant document will contain information about the
literacy rate in an African country.
General education levels that do not specifically include literacy rates
are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 699

</num><title>
term limits 

</title><desc>
What are the pros and cons of term limits?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents reflect an opinion on the value of term limits
with accompanying reason(s).  Documents that cite the status of term
limit legislation or opinions on the issue sans reasons for the opinion
are not relevant.
</narr></top>


<top>
<num> 700

</num><title>
gasoline tax U.S.

</title><desc>
What are the arguments for and against an increase in gasoline
taxes in the U.S.?

</desc><narr>
Relevant documents present reasons for or against raising gasoline taxes
in the U.S.  Documents discussing rises or decreases in the price of
gasoline are not relevant.
</narr></top>
</topics>
